Finding Aid for the Louis Jolyon West Papers LSC.0590
UCLA Library Special Collections
- 7. Research Files., 1890-1996.
  - 7.1 Research A to Z., 1890-1996.
    - Holocaust., 1967-1968, 1974, 1977-1982. (Box 129, Folder 8)
      Contains materials related to the "International Conference on the Holocaust and Genocide," and materials related to Sherry Terzian, Director of the NPI Mental Health Information Service.
    - Holocaust--Survival., 1966-1968, 1970, 1975, 1978. (Box 129, Folder 9)
    - Holocaust--Adolf Eichmann, newspaper clippings., 1961-1962. (Box 129, Folder 10)
    - Holocaust--Adolf Eichmann, correspondence., 1961-1962. (Box 129, Folder 11)
      Folder includes "An Open Letter to The People of Israel" regarding the death penalty for Adolf Eichmann.
    - Holocaust--Newspaper clippings and articles., 1968, 1975, 1977-1978. (Box 129, Folder 12)
    - Holzman, Philip., 1973-1978, 1980-1981. (Box 130, Folder 1)
      Conducted research on eye movement and schizophrenia.
    - Homeless., ca. 1988-1989. (Box 130, Folder 2)
    - "Homeless Adolescents: A Population in Crisis" (Folder 1 of 2)., 1974, 1988. (Box 130, Folder 3)
      Folder contains materials related to a conference on this topic, held on December 2, 1988.
    - "Homeless Adolescents: A Population in Crisis" (Folder 2 of 2)., 1974, 1988. (Box 130, Folder 4)
    - Homeless mentally ill., 1985, 1990. (Box 130, Folder 5)
    - Homeless mentally ill veterans., 1988-1989. (Box 130, Folder 6)
    - Homosexuality--Articles., 1953, 1967-1971, 1978. (Box 130, Folder 7)
    - Homosexuality--Gay Activists Alliance., 1973. (Box 130, Folder 8)
    - Homosexuality--Homosexuality in the military (Folder 1 of 2)., 1945, 1950, 1952-1955, 1958-1962, 1976, 1993. (Box 130, Folder 9)
    - Homosexuality--Homosexuality in the military, LJW's writing., 1950, 1955-1956, 1960, 1963. (Box 131, Folder 1)
    - Homosexuality--"A Psychiatric Evaluation of Laws of Homosexuality"., undated. (Box 131, Folder 2)
      An article by Karl M. Bowman, M.D. and Bernice Engle, M.A.
    - Hospitals--Articles and newspaper clippings., 1981, 1983-1986. (Box 131, Folder 3)
    - Hospitals--Ossining hospital crisis., 1983. (Box 131, Folder 4)
    - Hostages., 1977, 1979-1982, 1986, 1990, 1992. (Box 131, Folder 5)
    - Hostages--"Predictors of Rehabilitation Success for Political Prisoners"., 1980 February 1. (Box 131, Folder 6)
    - Hostages--Iranian Hostage Crisis., 1981, 1985. (Box 131, Folder 7)
    - Hostages--Other international hostage situations., 1973-1976, 1979-1980, 1982 1986. (Box 131, Folder 8)
    - Hughes, Howard., 1976. (Box 131, Folder 9)
    - Human subjects., 1973-1974. (Box 131, Folder 10)
    - Human subjects--Patient's rights., 1974-1975. (Box 131, Folder 11)
    - Humanism., 1984. (Box 131, Folder 12)
    - Hyperactivity--Attention Deficit Disorder., 1987. (Box 131, Folder 13)
    - Hypnosis--Articles (Folder 1 of 2)., 1972, 1977, 1989-1990. (Box 131, Folder 14)
    - Hypnosis--Articles (Folder 2 of 2)., 1972, 1975, 1981-1989, 1992. (Box 132, Folder 1)
    - Hypnosis--Reprints by authors with last names "A" and "B"., 1948-1949, 1954, 1958-1963. (Box 132, Folder 2)
    - Hypnosis--Reprints by authors with last names "C" through "F"., 1937, 1939, 1948-1952, 1955-1961. (Box 132, Folder 3)
    - Hypnosis--Reprints by authors with last names "G" through "J"., 1949, 1959-1963. (Box 132, Folder 4)
    - Hypnosis--Reprints by authors with last names "K" through "N"., 1947, 1951, 1955, 1958-1962, 1964, 1969-1970. (Box 132, Folder 5)
    - Hypnosis--Reprints by authors with last names "O" through "S"., 1950, 1956, 1958-1962, 1968, 1970. (Box 132, Folder 6)
    - Hypnosis--Reprints by authors with last names "T" through "Z"., 1936, 1960-1962, 1965, 1978, 1980-1982. (Box 133, Folder 1)
    - Hypnosis--Unpublished articles by authors with last names "A" through "Q"., 1959-1961, 1981. (Box 133, Folder 2)
    - Hypnosis--Unpublished articles by authors with last names "R" through "Z"., ca. 1961, ca. 1970. (Box 133, Folder 3)
    - Hypnosis--Unpublished reports for the United States Air Force by LJW., 1952-1953. (Box 133, Folder 4)
    - Hypnosis--"The Problem of Hypnotizability"., 1962. (Box 133, Folder 5)
      Unpublished paper by LJW and Gordon Harmon Deckert.
    - Hypnosis--Unpublished papers by LJW., 1948, ca. 1955-1957, 1961, 1973. (Box 133, Folder 6)
      Folder contains a 1948 paper "Hypnosis in Psychotherapy"written by LJW when in medical school.
    - Hypnosis--British Journal of Medical Hypnosis., 1949-1950. (Box 133, Folder 7)
    - Hypnosis--Case report and query., 1983-1984. (Box 133, Folder 8)
    - Hypnosis--Stanford Hypnotic Susceptibility Scale., 1962-1963. (Box 133, Folder 9)
    - Hypnosis--Legal., 1982. (Box 133, Folder 10)
    - Hypnosis--Hypnosis symposium., 1970-1971. (Box 133, Folder 11)
    - Hypnosis--Highway project., 1956-1957. (Box 134, Folder 1)
    - Hypnosis--Correspondence., 1959-1962, 1966, 1969-1971. (Box 134, Folder 2)
    - Hypnosis--Newspaper clippings., 1955, 1970, 1991. (Box 134, Folder 3)
    - Hypnosis and smoking (Folder 1 of 3)., 1976, 1979-1980, 1983, 1985-1988. (Box 134, Folder 4)
    - Hypnosis and smoking (Folder 2 of 3)., 1970, 1975-1980, 1982-1986, 1988. (Box 134, Folder 5)
    - Hypnosis and smoking (Folder 3 of 3)., 1969, 1977, 1979, 1983, 1988. (Box 134, Folder 6)
    - Hyrax research., 1936, 1962, 1965, 1967, 1970, 1972, 1975. (Box 134, Folder 7)
    - Imagination Workshop., 1979, 1981-1982. (Box 134, Folder 8)
    - Impaired physicians., 1981. (Box 134, Folder 9)
    - Impotence., 1983. (Box 134, Folder 10)
    - Indians., 1990. (Box 134, Folder 11)
    - Influence., 1992. (Box 134, Folder 12)
    - Insanity defense., 1983-1984, 1992. (Box 134, Folder 13)
    - Iran situations (Folder 1 of 2)., 1962-1964. (Box 134, Folder 14)
      Folder contains materials related to Iran, Air Force resistance training, and Late-Onset and Temporal Lobe Epilepsy.
    - Iran situations (Folder 2 of 2)., 1961-1964. (Box 135, Folder 1)
    - Isolation., undated. (Box 135, Folder 2)
    - Itil, Turan., 1981-1982. (Box 135, Folder 3)
    - Jamison, Kay., 1980, 1982, 1985. (Box 135, Folder 4)
      See also "Affective Disorder."
    - Javits, Jacob., 1983-1984. (Box 135, Folder 5)
    - Ketamine (Folder 1 of 2)., 1971-1973, 1976, 1980, 1982, 1985-1987, 1989-1990, 1992-1994. (Box 135, Folder 6)
    - Ketamine (Folder 2 of 2)., 1974, 1978, 1981, 1986, 1988, 1992-1993. (Box 135, Folder 7)
    - Kissing., 1994. (Box 135, Folder 8)
    - Kroger, William., 1979, 1981, 1986. (Box 135, Folder 9)
    - Kupfer, David (Folder 1 of 2)., 1971, 1975-1976, 1978-1981. (Box 135, Folder 10)
    - Kupfer, David (Folder 2 of 2)., 1971, 1975-1976, 1978-1981. (Box 136, Folder 1)
    - Laughter., 1939, 1982-1984. (Box 136, Folder 2)
    - Law and psychiatry (Folder 1 of 2)., 1950, 1963, 1979-1983. (Box 136, Folder 3)
    - Law and psychiatry (Folder 2 of 2)., 1974, 1980, 1982. (Box 136, Folder 4)
    - Law and psychiatry--Martin Auerbach., 1970-1971. (Box 136, Folder 5)
    - Law and psychiatry--David Bazelon., 1966, 1971-1972. (Box 136, Folder 6)
    - Law and Society--Bone marrow transplants., 1978. (Box 136, Folder 7)
    - Leaders and stress (Folder 1 of 2)., ca. 1989. (Box 136, Folder 8)
    - Leaders and stress (Folder 2 of 2)., ca. 1989. (Box 137, Folder 1)
    - Left-handedness., 1953, 1959. (Box 137, Folder 2)
    - Lethal injection., 1953, 1980-1981. (Box 137, Folder 3)
      See also "Capital punishment."
    - Lobotomy., 1988. (Box 137, Folder 4)
    - Los Angeles riots--UCLA Neuropsychiatric Institute's role., 1992. (Box 137, Folder 5)
    - LSD--Articles., 1962, 1973-1974, 1985-1988, 1990-1991. (Box 137, Folder 6)
      See also "Drugs and drug abuse," "Elephant," "Hallucination," "Haight- Ashbury."
    - LSD--Data and research., 1990-1991. (Box 137, Folder 7)
    - LSD--LJW's talks., 1990-1991. (Box 137, Folder 8)
    - Maggio, Elio., 1981. (Box 137, Folder 9)
    - Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI)., 1982, 1985. (Box 137, Folder 10)
    - Mandell, Arnold., 1978-1979. (Box 137, Folder 11)
    - Marijuana., 1968, 1979, 1993. (Box 138, Folder 1)
      See also "Cannibis."
    - Masserman, Jules., 1982. (Box 138, Folder 2)
    - Medical costs., 1985, 1990, 1993. (Box 138, Folder 3)
    - Medical education--Bibliography., 1966. (Box 138, Folder 4)
    - Medical education--Newspaper clippings., 1971, 1973, 1982. (Box 138, Folder 5)
    - Medical education--Ivory tower., 1964, 1966, 1973. (Box 138, Folder 6)
    - Medical education--Correspondence and meetings., 1970-1971. (Box 138, Folder 7)
    - Medical education--Nursing., 1971. (Box 138, Folder 8)
    - Medicine and health., 1986, 1990. (Box 138, Folder 9)
    - Meditation., 1976-1978. (Box 138, Folder 10)
      See also "Index cards: Meditation bibliographies"
    - Meditation--Transcendental Medication ("TM")., 1974-1976. (Box 138, Folder 11)
    - Meditation--Transcendental Medication ("TM") reprints., 1970, 1973-1977. (Box 138, Folder 12)
    - Meditation--Transcendental Medication ("TM"), physicians and physiology., 1970, 1972-1973, 1979. (Box 138, Folder 13)
    - Meditation--Transcendental Medication ("TM") and the mind., 1970-1972. (Box 138, Folder 14)
    - Meditation--Transcendental Medication ("TM") correspondence., 1972, 1975-1977. (Box 138, Folder 15)
    - Meditation--Transcendental Medication ("TM") and prisons (Folder 1 of 2)., ca. 1974. (Box 138, Folder 16)
    - Meditation--Transcendental Medication ("TM") and prisons (Folder 2 of 2)., 1974, 1976. (Box 139, Folder 1)
    - Meditation--Transcendental Medication ("TM") and drug abuse., 1972, 1975. (Box 139, Folder 2)
    - Meditation--Transcendental Medication ("TM") newsletters., 1971-1975. (Box 139, Folder 3)
    - Meditation--Transcendental Medication ("TM") newspaper clippings., 1973. (Box 139, Folder 4)
    - Meditation--Maharishi International University., 1973-1975. (Box 139, Folder 5)
    - Meditation--Ananda Marga., 1976. (Box 139, Folder 6)
    - Meditation--Oriental meditation, not TM., 1974, 1977-1978. (Box 139, Folder 7)
    - Meditation and psychotherapy., 1974-1978. (Box 139, Folder 8)
    - Megavitamin therapy., 1972-1973, 1975-1977, 1980. (Box 139, Folder 9)
    - Memory., 1980, 1984-1986, 1991. (Box 139, Folder 10)
    - Mental health--State of California, Tom Bradley's statement., 1981-1982. (Box 139, Folder 11)
    - Mental health--Newspaper clippings., 1970-1972. (Box 139, Folder 12)
    - Mental health--LJW on Community Psychiatry., 1977. (Box 139, Folder 13)
    - Mental health--Urban mental health, Manhattan project., 1977. (Box 139, Folder 14)
    - Mental health--Reports., 1986. (Box 140, Folder 1)
    - Mental health--Statistical Note journal., 1985, 1988. (Box 140, Folder 2)
    - Mental health--Costs., ca. 1989-1990. (Box 140, Folder 3)
    - Mental health--Epidemiological studies., ca. 1974, 1984, 1987-1989, 1992. (Box 140, Folder 4)
    - Mental health services (Folder 1 of 2)., 1983, 1991-1994. (Box 140, Folder 5)
    - Mental health services (Folder 2 of 2)., 1988-1993. (Box 140, Folder 6)
    - Mental health services--Delivery of services., 1985-1987, 1993. (Box 140, Folder 7)
    - Mental health services--Costs., 1982. (Box 141, Folder 1)
    - Mental health services--Torture., 1976, 1980, 1984, 1987, 1989-1991. (Box 141, Folder 2)
    - Mental health services--Rape., 1991. (Box 141, Folder 3)
    - Mental health services--Suicide., 1974, 1979, 1982, 1986-1987, 1991. (Box 141, Folder 4)
    - Mental health services--Homicide., 1986, 1990-1991. (Box 141, Folder 5)
    - Mental health services--Victims., 1987-1988, 1991. (Box 141, Folder 6)
    - Mental health services--Child abuse., 1985, 1987, 1990-1991. (Box 141, Folder 7)
    - Mental health services--Medical students (Folder 1 of 2)., 1973, 1976, 1980-1985, 1989-1990. (Box 141, Folder 8)
    - Mental health services--Medical students (Folder 2 of 2)., 1973-1974, 1976, 1979-1984. (Box 141, Folder 9)
    - Mental illness., 1949-1955. (Box 141, Folder 10)
    - Mesmer., 1981. (Box 141, Folder 11)
      See also "Hypnotism."
    - Middle East., 1973-1974, 1982. (Box 142, Folder 1)
      See also "Iran situations."
    - Military--Newspaper clippings., 1991, 1995. (Box 142, Folder 2)
    - Military--Airline sabotage., 1956, 1958, 1960, 1962, 1964. (Box 142, Folder 3)
    - Military--Airline accidents., 1962, 1969. (Box 142, Folder 4)
    - Military--Airline Pilots Association., 1956, 1964-1967. (Box 142, Folder 5)
    - Military--Airport insurance., 1962, 1964-1965. (Box 142, Folder 6)
    - Military--Articles on pilots., 1958, 1968. (Box 142, Folder 7)
    - Military--U.S. Air Force survival training., 1965. (Box 142, Folder 8)
    - Military--Department of Veterans Affairs., 1972. (Box 142, Folder 9)
    - Military--Senate bills on Veterans Affairs., 1971. (Box 142, Folder 10)
    - Military--Traumatic War Neuroses., 1943. (Box 142, Folder 11)
    - Military--Combat exhaustion., 1981. (Box 142, Folder 12)
    - Military--Drug use., 1972-1976. (Box 143, Folder 1)
    - Military--Sleep., 1973-1974, 1976-1978. (Box 143, Folder 2)
    - Military--Geriatrics., 1967. (Box 143, Folder 3)
    - Military--Reenlistment., 1975. (Box 143, Folder 4)
    - Military--Newspaper clippings., 1953, 1971. (Box 143, Folder 5)
    - Military--Michael Jones., 1976. (Box 143, Folder 6)
    - Military--Military murder., 1975. (Box 143, Folder 7)
    - Military--Shraver case., 1954-1955, 1958, 1961. (Box 143, Folder 8)
    - Military--Naval Health Research Center., 1974-1978, 1982. (Box 143, Folder 9)
    - Mindlin, Eugene., 1979. (Box 143, Folder 10)
    - Mindszenty, Cardinal., 1991. (Box 143, Folder 11)
      See also "Prisoners of War"
    - Minnesota Multiphasic Personality Inventory (MMPI)., 1970. (Box 143, Folder 12)
    - Mitchelson, Marvin M.--Book proposal for "No Pal O' Mine: The Secret Life of Famed Palimony Attorney Marvin M. Mitchelson," by Nina Iliescu, Linda Acaldo, and P.J. Thomas., ca. 1989. (Box 143, Folder 13)
    - Mountain climbing., 1959-1960. (Box 143, Folder 14)
    - Multiple myeloma articles., 1989-1990. (Box 143, Folder 15)
    - Munchausen, the Baron., 1983. (Box 143, Folder 16)
    - Myth and mythology., ca. 1980-1989. (Box 143, Folder 17)
    - National Research Council News Report., 1986 November. (Box 144, Folder 1)
    - Neuropsychiatric Institute (UCLA)--Functional Description., 1982. (Box 144, Folder 2)
    - Neuropsychiatric Institute (UCLA)--Annual Report., 1973-1975. (Box 144, Folder 3)
    - Neuropsychiatric Institute (UCLA)--history and correspondence., 1956, 1957, 1961, 1970, 1972, 1976. (Box 144, Folder 4)
    - Neuropsychiatric Institute (UCLA)--"An Ethnography of MRCP: A General's Guide to the Hazards of Tripping Over Your Own Sword," by John C. Russell., 1985. (Box 144, Folder 5)
    - Neuropsychiatric Institute (UCLA)--facts and numbers., 1985-1987. (Box 144, Folder 6)
    - Neuropsychiatric Institute (UCLA)--Academic Plan., 1984. (Box 144, Folder 7)
    - Neurosciences--"The Neurosciences at UCLA: A Report of the Blue Ribbon Commission on the Neurosciences"., 1989. (Box 144, Folder 8)
    - Neurosciences--UCLA correspondence., 1989. (Box 144, Folder 9)
    - Neurosis--articles., 1944-1945, 1951, 1961, 1963. (Box 144, Folder 10)
    - Neurosis--Incapacitating., ca. 1975. (Box 144, Folder 11)
    - Neurosis-Traumatic., 1970, 1976. (Box 144, Folder 12)
    - Niederland, William G.., 1968, 1972, 1974-1976, 1979-1981. (Box 144, Folder 13)
    - Nobel Foundation--Isaac Bashevis Singer lecture., 1978. (Box 144, Folder 14)
    - Nuclear Disarmament--"Nuclear Disarmament and the Family Complex," by Anne Henderson., 1985. (Box 144, Folder 15)
    - Nuclear Magnetic Resonance--articles., 1983-1984. (Box 144, Folder 16)
    - Obsessive-Compulsion., 1989. (Box 144, Folder 17)
    - Pain--Chronic (1 of 2)., 1978-1981. (Box 144, Folder 18)
    - Pain--Chronic (2 of 2)., 1981 May. (Box 145, Folder 1)
      National Institute on Drug Abuse Research Monograph Series 36
    - Pain--Research., 1950-1952. (Box 145, Folder 2)
    - Panic., 1988, 1991. (Box 145, Folder 3)
      See also "Anxiety Disorders"
    - Parapsychology and ESP--articles by authors with last names "A" through "G"., 1958, 1960, 1966, 1970, 1978-1979, 1981, 1983, 1987. (Box 145, Folder 4)
      See also "Supernatural"
    - Parapsychology and ESP--articles by authors with last names "H" through "Q"., 1950, 1953, 1955-1956, 1966, 1968-1970, 1977, 1979, 1981-1982, 1986- 1988, 1992. (Box 145, Folder 5)
    - Parapsychology and ESP--articles by authors with last names "R" through "Z"., 1954, 1956, 1966, 1969, 1972, 1975, 1979, 1981-1982, 1985-1989, 1991. (Box 145, Folder 6)
      Includes LJW, "A Note on the Strange Case of 'Bridey Murphy.'" See also "Supernatural"
    - Parapsychology and ESP--correspondence, bibliography, biographical materials., 1974, 1976-1979, 1991-1992. (Box 145, Folder 7)
      Includes J. Guy Edwards and David Gill, "Psychiatry and the Occult"; Kendrick Frazier, "Science and the Parascience Cults"; Charles S. Rebert, "EEG Spectrum Analysis Techniques Applied to the Problem of PSI Phenomena"; SRI International materials. See also "Cults" files, "Supernatural"
    - Peace Corps--correspondence., 1962, 1964. (Box 146, Folder 1)
    - Peace Corps--articles., 1959, 1961-1964. (Box 146, Folder 2)
    - Peace Corps--Research Notes, newsletters, report and guidelines., 1962-1965. (Box 146, Folder 3)
    - Periodicity., 1960. (Box 146, Folder 4)
    - PET scan., ca. 1984. (Box 146, Folder 5)
    - Physicians--suicide articles., 1973-1976, 1978-1980. (Box 146, Folder 6)
      See also "Suicide--Physicians and suicide"
    - Physicians--marriage and family articles., 1965, 1972-1974, 1976-1982. (Box 146, Folder 7)
    - Physicians--substance abuse articles., 1972-1978, 1981, 1984. (Box 146, Folder 8)
    - Physicians--health and stress articles (1 of 2)., 1972, 1974-1984. (Box 147, Folder 1)
    - Physicians--health and stress articles (2 of 2)., 1971, 1973, 1975, 1977- 1979, 1981-1985. (Box 147, Folder 2)
    - Physicians--miscellaneous materials on health and stress., 1970-1972, 1974, 1977-1982, 1984-1985. (Box 147, Folder 3)
    - Pilowsky, I.., 1972, 1975-1979. (Box 147, Folder 4)
    - Polar Biomedical Research., 1985. (Box 147, Folder 5)
    - Police--articles by authors with last names "A" through "G"., 1972, 1979-1980, 1982, 1984-1989. (Box 147, Folder 6)
    - Police--articles by authors with last names "H" through "N"., 1970, 1976-1977, 1984-1986, 1988. (Box 147, Folder 7)
    - Police--articles by authors with last names "P" through "Z"., 1968, 1975-1976, 1979, 1984-1985, 1987-1990. (Box 148, Folder 1)
    - Police--bibliography., 1991. (Box 148, Folder 2)
    - Police--"Unwonted Violence by Police Officers," by LJW; Christopher Commission report., 1991. (Box 148, Folder 3)
    - Police--Nels Klyver and LAPD research., 1971, 1974, 1977-1978, 1984, 1986-1987, 1990-1991,. (Box 148, Folder 4)
    - Police--"Medical Standards for Police and Fire Service," City of Los Angeles., 1991. (Box 148, Folder 5)
    - Police--Psychiatric Emergency Coordinating Committee., 1991. (Box 148, Folder 6)
    - Police--psychological and psychiatric evaluation., 1991. (Box 148, Folder 7)
    - Politicians and psychiatry., 1974. (Box 148, Folder 8)
    - Politics--New Left., 1969. (Box 148, Folder 9)
    - Population--"Department of Health, Education, and Welfare Report on Population and Family Planning Activities"., 1969. (Box 149, Folder 1)
    - Post, Robert M. (1 of 2)., 1981. (Box 149, Folder 2)
    - Post, Robert M. (2 of 2)., 1981. (Box 149, Folder 3)
    - Post Traumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD)--Bibliography., 1984, 1986-1987. (Box 149, Folder 4)
      See also "Trauma"
    - Post Traumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD)--articles by authors with last names "A" through "K"., 1964, 1969, 1975, 1978, 1981-1989, 1991. (Box 149, Folder 5)
    - Post Traumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD)--articles by authors with last names "L" through "R"., 1971, 1975-1976, 1978, 1980, 1982-1986, 1988-1991. (Box 149, Folder 6)
    - Post Traumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD)--articles by authors with last names "S" through "Z"., 1970, 1982-1989. (Box 150, Folder 1)
    - Post Traumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD)--Vietnam War (1 of 3)., 1979-1982, 1984. (Box 150, Folder 2)
    - Post Traumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD)--Vietnam War (2 of 3)., 1983. (Box 150, Folder 3)
      Contains dissertation, "The Interpersonal and Dyadic Functioning of Vietnam Veterans with Posttraumatic Stress Disorder," by Edward M. Carroll.
    - Post Traumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD)--Vietnam War (3 of 3)., 1987. (Box 150, Folder 4)
      Articles for the Journal of Clinical Psychology 43.1 (January 1987).
    - Post Traumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD)--Holocaust., 1971, 1981, 1983-1985, 1987, 1989, 1991, 1994,. (Box 150, Folder 5)
    - Post Traumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD)--Children., 1979, 1984-1986. (Box 150, Folder 6)
      Includes materials for LJW chapter for APA monograph entitled Post Traumatic Stress Disorder in Children
    - Post Traumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD)--nosology, symptoms, and treatment., ca. 1980, 1983, 1994. (Box 151, Folder 1)
    - Post Traumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD) and torture--correspondence., 1982-1986, 1989. (Box 151, Folder 2)
      Includes pamphlet "I Was Tortured in the Pasadena Jailhouse!" by Bobby Fischer
    - Post Traumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD--bibliography, LJW article and presentation drafts., 1985-1986. (Box 151, Folder 3)
    - Post Traumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD) and torture--news clippings., 1980, 1984-1986, 1989-1990. (Box 151, Folder 4)
    - Poverty--Economic Opportunity Act of 1964 and Job Corps., 1964-1965. (Box 151, Folder 5)
    - Prisoners of war (P.O.W.s)--news clippings and broadcast., 1956-1957, 1991. (Box 151, Folder 6)
    - Prisoners of war (P.O.W.s)--P.O.W. research project correspondence and contracts (1 of 3)., 1950, 1955-1958. (Box 151, Folder 7)
    - Prisoners of war (P.O.W.s)--P.O.W. research project research correspondence (2 of 3)., 1956-1957. (Box 151, Folder 8)
    - Prisoners of war (P.O.W.s)--P.O.W. research project research correspondence (3 of 3)., 1956-1957. (Box 151, Folder 9)
      Correspondence with Samuel M. Meyers and Albert D. Biderman.
    - Prisoners of war (P.O.W.s)--P.O.W. research project travel., 1957. (Box 151, Folder 10)
    - Prisoners of war (P.O.W.s)--Oklahoma Medical Research Foundation P.O.W. research project bibliography (1 of 2)., 1956. (Box 152, Folder 1)
    - Prisoners of war (P.O.W.s)--Oklahoma Medical Research Foundation P.O.W. research project bibliography (2 of 2)., 1956-1957. (Box 152, Folder 2)
    - Prisoners of war (P.O.W.s)--research project proposal., ca. 1956. (Box 152, Folder 3)
    - Prisoners of war (P.O.W.s)--Oklahoma Medical Research Foundation P.O.W. research project quarterly progress reports., 1956-1957. (Box 152, Folder 4)
    - Prisoners of war (P.O.W.s)--literature review., ca. 1956. (Box 152, Folder 5)
    - Prisoners of war (P.O.W.s)--P.O.W. research project security clearance., 1956-1957. (Box 152, Folder 6)
    - Prisoners of war (P.O.W.s)--Korea., 1954. (Box 152, Folder 7)
    - Prisoners of war (P.O.W.s)--P.O.W. research project papers and materials by LJW., ca. 1957. (Box 152, Folder 8)
    - Prisoners of war (P.O.W.s)--"Student instructions… P.O.W. compound exercise"., ca. 1957 [?]. (Box 152, Folder 9)
    - Prisoners of war (P.O.W.s)--Notes on false confessions., 1956-1957. (Box 152, Folder 10)
    - Prisoners of war (P.O.W.s)--Health consequences., ca. 1991. (Box 152, Folder 11)
    - Prisoners of war (P.O.W.s)--Miscellaneous articles., ca. 1958, ca. 1991. (Box 152, Folder 12)
    - Prisoners of war (P.O.W.s)--Stress., 1954-1955, 1962. (Box 152, Folder 13)
    - Prisoners of war (P.O.W.s)--Refugees, POW deaths., 1975-1977. (Box 152, Folder 14)
    - Prisoners of war (P.O.W.s)--Unpublished writing by LJW., ca. 1955. (Box 152, Folder 15)